<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-30T15:53:25-04:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Foreign Merchants of Socotra</title><subtitle>During the early first millennium CE the island of Socotra, off the coasts of Yemen and Somalia, was a hubb of traders from all corners of the Indian Ocean. This website aims to gather all the primary sources on the island in a centralized digital space.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Indian Inscriptions</title><link href="/Indian_Inscriptions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Indian Inscriptions" /><published>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</updated><id>/Indian_inscriptions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Indian_Inscriptions/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;inscriptions-from-indian-merchants-on-socotra&quot;&gt;Inscriptions from Indian Merchants on Socotra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;brahmi-inscription-1112-from-the-hoq-cave-in-socotra&quot;&gt;Brahmi Inscription 11:12 from the Hoq Cave in Socotra&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/11-12.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Inscription 11:12&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provenance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hoq Cave in Socotra, Yemen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2nd-4th c. CE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original text&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
bhārukacchaka&lt;br /&gt;
niryyāmaka visnudharo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The captain Visnudhara from Bharukaccha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentary by Mikhail D. Bukharin (From Strauch 2012, 132):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the only epigraph where the professional designation &lt;i&gt;niryāmaka&lt;/i&gt; occurs. It is semantically closely connected with the lexeme &lt;i&gt;nāvika&lt;/i&gt;. According to the literary and lexicographical sources both terms designate a leading member of the ship-crew, either the captain, the steersman or the pilot. For lack of any possibility to fix a more narrow meaning both terms are treated here as synonymous and translated as “captain.” Paleographically remarkable are the cursive shapes of &lt;i&gt;bhā&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;ro&lt;/i&gt;. The southern shape of the &lt;i&gt;ro&lt;/i&gt; in combination with the open-mouthed northern ma indicate a date between the 2nd and 4th c. CE. The distinct horizontal headmark of k- makes it impossible to discern a diacritic -o in &lt;i&gt;bhārukacchaka&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;niryyāmaka&lt;/i&gt;. Due to the identical shape of ka in &lt;i&gt;bhārukacchaka&lt;/i&gt;, the present reading is preferred here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Inscriptions" /><summary type="html">Inscriptions from Indian Merchants on Socotra</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greek Inscriptions</title><link href="/Greek_Inscriptions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greek Inscriptions" /><published>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</updated><id>/greek-inscriptions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Greek_Inscriptions/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;inscriptions-from-greek-merchants-on-socotra&quot;&gt;Inscriptions from Greek Merchants on Socotra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;greek-inscription-1128-from-the-hoq-cave-in-socotra&quot;&gt;Greek Inscription 11:28 from the Hoq Cave in Socotra&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/11-28.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Inscription 11:28&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provenance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hoq Cave in Socotra, Yemen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2nd-4th c. CE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original text&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
μνηθη&lt;br /&gt;
Αλεξαν&lt;br /&gt;
δρος Πετ(ρ)&lt;br /&gt;
ος&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Let Alexandros,&lt;br /&gt;
[son of] Petros,&lt;br /&gt;
be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternate translations:&lt;br /&gt;
“Let Alexandros, [baptised] Petros, be remembered.”&lt;br /&gt;
Or “Let Alexandros be remembered. Petros.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentary by Mikhail D. Bukharin (From Strauch 2012, 144):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The text is limited by a horizontal line. Since the stalactite is curved, the ends of lines 1 and 3 are difficult to discern. The vertical bar of the last sign in line 3 (ρ) was either written in a fissure or was later covered with a flow and now resembles a split in the wall. Thus, only the round element of this sign is now seen. The shape of the ρ following the letter δ (line 3) suggests that this sign was omitted and added only later, after the inscription had been finished: it is narrower than the other letters.For an interpretation of the contents of this graffito see Bukharin, infra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bibliography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Strauch, Ingo (Ed.). “Foreign Sailors on Socotra: The Inscriptions and Drawings from the Cave Hoq.” Hempen Verlag, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;greek-inscription-1126-from-the-hoq-cave-in-socotra&quot;&gt;Greek Inscription 11:26 from the Hoq Cave in Socotra&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/11-26.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Inscription 11:26&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provenance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Hoq Cave in Socotra, Yemen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 2nd-4th c. CE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original text&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Σεπτιμιος&lt;br /&gt;
Πανισκος&lt;br /&gt;
ναυκληρος&lt;br /&gt;
τους θεους&lt;br /&gt;
μετα και του&lt;br /&gt;
σπηλεου&lt;br /&gt;
προσεκυνησα&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Septimius Paniskus, the ship-owner,&lt;br /&gt;
kneeled before the gods and before (that/those) of the cave. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentary by Mikhail D. Bukharin (From Strauch 2012, 142):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This text is one of the very few Greek inscriptions found in the cave. Although the walls of the cave are covered with geological flows and fissures, reading of the text is not very problematic. Modern Arabic memorial graffiti complicate reading of the end of line 7, but do not make it impossible. The only damaged fragment begins after the second sign in line 6, but the context makes a restitution of η and the reading of the whole word as σπηλεου with the reduction ε – αι quite certain. Some paleographic features can be pointed out: the writing of η in the form of Latin h; the cursive writing of μ and α and the writing of ι as a vertical bar.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Inscriptions" /><summary type="html">Inscriptions from Greek Merchants on Socotra</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">South Arabian Inscriptions</title><link href="/South_Arabian_Inscriptions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="South Arabian Inscriptions" /><published>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</updated><id>/southarabian-inscriptions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/South_Arabian_Inscriptions/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;inscriptions-from-south-arabian-merchants-on-socotra&quot;&gt;Inscriptions from South Arabian Merchants on Socotra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;south-arabian-inscription-63-from-the-hoq-cave-in-socotra&quot;&gt;South Arabian Inscription 6:3 from the Hoq Cave in Socotra&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/6-3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Inscription 6:3&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provenance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hoq Cave in Socotra, Yemen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2nd-4th c. CE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original text&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
‘bds&lt;br /&gt;
y-bh’-f-kmk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Abdsiya est venu et tu t’es caché.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentary by Christian Julien Robin (From Strauch 2012, 94):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Texte tracé aved une pierre tendre, sur un rocher plat. […] Ce text est donc le plus ancien de tous ceux qui ont été relevés dans la grotte. 11. 1-2, ‘bds y: nom d’homme théophore, déjà attesté dans RES 4894 = Ja 990 = Pirenne al-‘Uqla sud d / 2; -sy est une forme abrégée de Syn, le grand dieu du Hadramawt. 1. 2, kmk: aucune trace du lettre ne reconnaît à gauche de kmk fait problème puisque la racine KMK n’est pas attestée. Faut-il supposer que la second k est le pronom suffixe de la diexième personne au singulier ou la désinence des dues premières personnes de l’accompli singulier? Nous retenons, faute de mieux, la seconde hypothèse et proposons que ‘Abdsiya reproche au maître de la grotte de ne pas s’être manifesté lors de sa visite. Voir kamma, “couvrir; boucher; être couvert” ou kamà, “taire, cacher; se mettre une cuirasse; au passif, être tout couvert d’une armure.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Inscriptions" /><summary type="html">Inscriptions from South Arabian Merchants on Socotra</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Socotra in Textual Sources</title><link href="/Textual_Sources_PME/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Socotra in Textual Sources" /><published>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T14:32:38-04:00</updated><id>/socotra-pme</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Textual_Sources_PME/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;periplus-maris-erythraei-on-the-island-of-socotra&quot;&gt;Periplus Maris Erythraei on the island of Socotra&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The island of Socotra appears in two passages of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Periplus_of_the_Erythraean_Sea&quot;&gt;Periplus Maris Erythraei&lt;/a&gt; under the name of Dioscurides Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;translation-by-casson&quot;&gt;Translation by &lt;a href=&quot;https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lionel_Casson&quot;&gt;Casson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30. On this bay is a mighty headland, facing the east, called Syagros, at which there are a fortress to guard the region, a harbor, and a storehouse for the collection of frankincense. In the open sea off it is an island, between it and the Promontory of Spices across the water but nearer to Syagros, called Dioscurides; though very large, it is barren and also damp, with rivers, crocodiles, a great many vipers, and huge lizards, so huge that people eat the flesh and melt down the fat to use in place of oil. The island bears no farm products, neither vines nor grain. The inhabitants, few in number, live on one side of the island, that
to the north, the part facing the mainland; they are settlers, a mixture of Arabs and Indians and even some Greeks, who sail out of there to trade. The island yields tortoise shell, the genuine, the land, and the light-colored, in great quantity and distinguished by rather large shields, and also the oversize mountain variety with an extremely thick shell, of which the parts over the belly, whichever are useful, do not take [sc. regular] cutting; besides, they are rather tawny. On the other hand, whatever can be used for small boxes, small plaques, small disks, and similar items gets cut up completely. The so-called Indian cinnabar is found there; it is collected as an exudation from the trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;31. The island is subject to the aforementioned king of the frankincense- bearing land, just as Azania is to Charibael and the governor of Mapharitis. Trade with it used to be carried on by some of the shippers from Muza and also by those sailing out of Limyrike and Barygaza who by chance put in at it; these would exchange rice, grain, cotton cloth, and female slaves, which found a market because of a shortage there, for big cargoes of tortoise shell. At the present time the kings have leased out the island, and it is under guard.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Textual" /><category term="Sources" /><summary type="html">Periplus Maris Erythraei on the island of Socotra</summary></entry></feed>